http://www.villierspark.org.uk/privacy-policy

About usTrusteesMeet the TeamOur StoryAlumniOur strategy Possible selvesFuture Leaders ProgrammeStaying with usSupport UsDonateFundraiseWorking with universitiesCompanies, charitable trusts and philanthropyOur supportersA-level emergency appealWhy Evaluate? conferenceOur ImpactNewsAchievements, ambitions and ideas - a Hastings and Bexhill Scholar interviews our new CEOWiltshire Freemasons pledge two year support towards our Swindon Scholars ProgrammeAspiring future STEM professionals join dedicated industry-focused Scholars programmeChairman of Essex County Council backs launch of educational programme described as 'life-changingMurwa's mentoring for English studentsRevision tips for home-schooled peersScholars attend Trinity College Cambridge's first residential for Year 11 students"Inspiring Excellence doesn't even come close to describing it""It's about finding the avenue that works best for you."Tyneside Scholar sets her sights on a future in medicineVilliers Park Educational Trust welcomes new Chief Executive OfficerLasting legacy for trustee committed to educationWhat makes a Villiers Park tutor?Forty-five Scholars set sights on early entry places100 seconds with... Guy Sutton"Being a Scholar has changed my life""Everything can change in a few years"What is a Villiers Park residential really like?“Villiers Park has definitely helped me do better than I ever thought possible.”Growing Up Gifted“I genuinely believe that going to Villiers Park was one of the best decisions I ever made.”Brain Power!Danger of fee cuts for social mobilityFundraising the Chrissy, Louise and Rachel Baker way!New hub aims to help universities eliminate equality gapsVilliers Park helped me to understand tuition fees“We’ve been sending students to Villiers Park for 30 years!”"He couldn't run around like other kids, so he immersed himself in learning."Enchiladas on a budget!From Science to StoriesState of the Nation: Villiers Park CEO on the Social Mobility Commission report"Being on the Scholars Programme makes me stand out!"Pro Bono Economics: Assessing the Impact of the Scholars Programme"I'm not afraid to be in the minority ... I want to go to Cambridge!"“Young carers have potential, but don’t have the chance to shine.”Happy Anniversary Scholars Programme!From Day One: Looking Back on the Scholars Programme“Immigrant students are surrounded by an invisible wall … Villiers Park helped me break it down.”Celebration video!Exam Results: Our adviceHeading out!Defending the UK: Former IEP student lands internship in Cyber SecurityChanging the Mindset: Supporting Early Entry StudentsMidexPRO: Celebrating 25 years and supporting Villiers ParkStudying medicine to improve Middle Eastern healthcare2020 STEM Scholar lands STEM job at her schoolTribute to Jack MerrittFrom Coast to CambridgeHuge growth in impact of INVOLVE leadership challengeOur Marathon ManEva's StoryPartnership with Rees Centre, Oxford aims to address educational challenges of young people in careEmma Campbell Trust Legacy GiftNovel Coronavirus (COVID-19) UpdateKeep Calm and Carry On-lineVilliers Scholar Liam on Growing Up GiftedCOVID-19 update from Villiers ParkDigital Divide could take social mobility back a decadeAppointment of our new ChairRemote YearningWhy Black Lives Matter to everyone at Villiers ParkWhat lockdown taught meShare Her Story: Women in STEMA Fantastic Future: Degree ApprenticeshipsA-level results statement from Villiers ParkA Levels: Students' questions answeredVilliers Park at the forefront of the fight for fair exam resultsPlanning for the future after getting exam resultsRae Tooth joins University of Winchester boardHigh-profile new trustees join Villiers ParkAbout usSupport Us
About usTrusteesMeet the TeamOur StoryAlumniOur strategy Possible selvesFuture Leaders ProgrammeStaying with usSupport UsDonateFundraiseWorking with universitiesCompanies, charitable trusts and philanthropyOur supportersA-level emergency appealWhy Evaluate? conferenceOur ImpactNewsAchievements, ambitions and ideas - a Hastings and Bexhill Scholar interviews our new CEOWiltshire Freemasons pledge two year support towards our Swindon Scholars ProgrammeAspiring future STEM professionals join dedicated industry-focused Scholars programmeChairman of Essex County Council backs launch of educational programme described as 'life-changingMurwa's mentoring for English studentsRevision tips for home-schooled peersScholars attend Trinity College Cambridge's first residential for Year 11 students"Inspiring Excellence doesn't even come close to describing it""It's about finding the avenue that works best for you."Tyneside Scholar sets her sights on a future in medicineVilliers Park Educational Trust welcomes new Chief Executive OfficerLasting legacy for trustee committed to educationWhat makes a Villiers Park tutor?Forty-five Scholars set sights on early entry places100 seconds with... Guy Sutton"Being a Scholar has changed my life""Everything can change in a few years"What is a Villiers Park residential really like?“Villiers Park has definitely helped me do better than I ever thought possible.”Growing Up Gifted“I genuinely believe that going to Villiers Park was one of the best decisions I ever made.”Brain Power!Danger of fee cuts for social mobilityFundraising the Chrissy, Louise and Rachel Baker way!New hub aims to help universities eliminate equality gapsVilliers Park helped me to understand tuition fees“We’ve been sending students to Villiers Park for 30 years!”"He couldn't run around like other kids, so he immersed himself in learning."Enchiladas on a budget!From Science to StoriesState of the Nation: Villiers Park CEO on the Social Mobility Commission report"Being on the Scholars Programme makes me stand out!"Pro Bono Economics: Assessing the Impact of the Scholars Programme"I'm not afraid to be in the minority ... I want to go to Cambridge!"“Young carers have potential, but don’t have the chance to shine.”Happy Anniversary Scholars Programme!From Day One: Looking Back on the Scholars Programme“Immigrant students are surrounded by an invisible wall … Villiers Park helped me break it down.”Celebration video!Exam Results: Our adviceHeading out!Defending the UK: Former IEP student lands internship in Cyber SecurityChanging the Mindset: Supporting Early Entry StudentsMidexPRO: Celebrating 25 years and supporting Villiers ParkStudying medicine to improve Middle Eastern healthcare2020 STEM Scholar lands STEM job at her schoolTribute to Jack MerrittFrom Coast to CambridgeHuge growth in impact of INVOLVE leadership challengeOur Marathon ManEva's StoryPartnership with Rees Centre, Oxford aims to address educational challenges of young people in careEmma Campbell Trust Legacy GiftNovel Coronavirus (COVID-19) UpdateKeep Calm and Carry On-lineVilliers Scholar Liam on Growing Up GiftedCOVID-19 update from Villiers ParkDigital Divide could take social mobility back a decadeAppointment of our new ChairRemote YearningWhy Black Lives Matter to everyone at Villiers ParkWhat lockdown taught meShare Her Story: Women in STEMA Fantastic Future: Degree ApprenticeshipsA-level results statement from Villiers ParkA Levels: Students' questions answeredVilliers Park at the forefront of the fight for fair exam resultsPlanning for the future after getting exam resultsRae Tooth joins University of Winchester boardHigh-profile new trustees join Villiers Park
Donate
Student Hub
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Our VisionToo many high ability young people from less advantaged backgrounds do not fulfil their potential. Villiers Park Educational Trust empowers young people to overcome the barriers to success, enabling them to become leaders in their field.Villiers Park Educational Trust is a registered charity. Our work is almost entirely funded through voluntary income thanks to the generosity of members of the public, charitable trusts, foundations, and philanthropic businesses and individuals.This policy explains how we use and protect your data as part of our work. Villiers Park Educational Trust promises to safely process and store your personal data. We strive to ensure that our paperwork and forms are clear about how we will use the data we collect.Data plays a big role in what we do. It is fundamental for the safe and effective running of our courses, programmes and our charity. The section on 'how we use your personal information' will explain how we use data about you. As per the section on 'what we collect', you may withdraw your consent for us to process your information at any time.What this policy is aboutThis privacy policy explains how Villiers Park Educational Trust (we) processes your personal information ('data'). In this policy, "processes" means collects, stores, shares and otherwise uses for lawful purposes. "We" and "our" means Villiers Park Educational Trust and it covers all the instances where we might process personal information of supporters, beneficiaries and other relevant parties of Villiers Park Educational Trust. This policy was updated in April 2018 to reflect the new data protection legislation called the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulation (PECR).If you have any questions about this policy or how we use your personal information, please contact us using the contact details given below.Organisations are permitted to process data if they have a legal basis in doing so. We process data when:We have express and informed consent given by the person whose data is being processed; and/orWe have a legitimate interest in processing the data; and/orIt is necessary in relation to a contract or agreement which the person has entered into or because the person has asked for something to be done so they can enter into a contract or agreement; and/orThere is a legal obligation on Villiers Park Educational Trust to process data.Where Villiers Park Educational Trust is relying solely on consent as the basis for processing data, we are required to obtain your expressed consent and you can modify or withdraw this consent at any time by notifying us in writing, although this may affect the extent to which we are we able to provide services to or interact with you in future.Villiers Park Educational Trust may change this policy from time to time and any such changes will be published on our website. Notwithstanding any change to this policy, we will continue to process your personal data in accordance with your rights and our obligations in law.Your personal information: what we collectThe personal information we collect about you will depend on whether you are supporting us by giving a gift, a student participating in one of our activities, signing up to our mentor scheme, registering your child on a programme or course, applying for a job, volunteering vacancy or expressing interest in supporting us. It may include (but isn't limited to):your name, address, telephone number, date of birth, gender and email address;debit or credit card information, your bank account number, sort code and other banking information, information required to validate your identity and prevent fraud;your preferences and interests, we may utilise your preferences to ensure we send you the most relevant communication in the future;other information you provide to us from time to time which is relevant and necessary for us to collect and processyour activity online concerning your visit/s to our website and when we send you an emailinformation on your family or background, current or former circumstances, specifically so that we can assist you further or benefit from your support;You, as the data subject, may change your preferences or request deletion of your data at any time in writing, subject to any overriding legal obligation that we may have for its retention. We may keep such data on a 'suppression list' so we know not to contact you or process your data in future until further notice.You also have the right to raise any issues of concern about us regarding data protection and our processing of your information to the data protection regulator, The Information Commissioner's Office (ICO). Here is a helpful link to their website.https://ico.org.uk/concerns/We would also never sell your information to a third party.Supporter profiles:We use profiling and screening techniques to ensure communications are relevant and timely, and provide an improved experience for our supporters. Profiling allows us to target our resources effectively, which we know will be important to our supporters. We do this because it allows us to understand the background of the people who support us and it helps us to make appropriate requests to supporters who may be able and willing to give more than they already do. Importantly, it enables us to raise more funds, sooner and more cost-effectively than we otherwise would.When building a profile we may analyse geographic, demographic and other information relating to you in order to better understand your interests, preferences and motivation for giving, in order to contact you with the most relevant communications. In doing this, we may use additional information from third party sources or publicly available sources. This could be, for example, addresses, education history, listed job titles or typical earnings in a given areaHow we use your personal informationWe use your personal information for the following purposes:to confirm that your donations and fees have been processed correctly or to validate your Gift Aid claim;for providing the relevant information to you regarding the work we do to support young people;for invoicing purposes when you donate to us;to send you administrative information, relating to our organisation and its activities, for example, information about a residential a young person is attending, where relevant;for our internal purposes such as management, research, analytics, organisational reporting, and ways that will improve efficiencies;to check with you that you are content with regards the type of communications that you receive;to market our events, fundraising opportunities, and other ways to get involved with Villiers Park Educational Trust, including occasionally third-party events or activities that may be of interest to you by the appropriate means and in accordance with the GDPR and the PECR.we may use of cookies and other similar technologies on our online channels or platforms to help you have a better experience when you engage with us;to help the emergency services if required;to prevent and detect criminal activity and fraud;to comply with applicable laws, regulations, court orders, government and law enforcement agencies' requests, to operate our systems properly and to protect ourselves, our beneficiaries and our supporters.Who we share your personal information withWe do not sell or share personal details to third parties for the purposes of marketing.If we run an event or fundraising activity, it may require the service of a third party and then we might need to share your details with them. This would happen if your data was required to deliver the specific activity, for example we would share your data with an outsourced mailing house provider, in order for us to send you a fundraising appeal.If we share your data with colleagues or programme partners, including outside of the European Union, we will only do so if we are confident that they adhere to the same high standards that we do when processing data and protecting its privacy and security.If we share your information with other organisations or data processors we do not allow them to use your information for their own purposes and they have to follow our strict instructions whilst complying with appropriate security measures. We regularly assess their security measures and we continue to monitor their compliance throughout the time we use their services.We may also share your data with law enforcement agencies, regulators, courts, public authorities or emergency services when required to do so.Cookies and other similar technologiesWe use cookies and similar technologies to collect and store information (which may include your personal information) about how you interact with our website. We may use these technologies to help us deliver relevant information about our organisation.Cookies are small text files placed on your device which uniquely identify your device. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your device.For more information about our use of these technologies please contact Christine Hall, Director of Finance.Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. Once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy policy. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy policy applicable to the website in question.How long we keep your personal informationThe period for which we keep your information depends on the purpose for which your information was collected and the use.  We will not keep your personal information for longer than necessary for those purposes or for any other legal requirements.We review all data retention periods every two years. Data collected for accounts purposes are kept for seven years plus an additional period of six months. You can request your data to be forgotten and we will delete all your data other than anything we have to retain for legal reasons.Keeping your personal information up to dateWe want to make sure that any personal information we hold about you is up to date. So if you think your personal information is inaccurate, you can ask us to correct or remove it at no charge to you. This is called your right to rectification. Please contact our office on 01223 872601 or dataprotection@villierspark.org.uk if you would like to change any information that we may hold on you.Under the GDPR, you have a right to know what personal information we hold about you. To request any information, please read the Subject Access Request policy and complete the form provided - all available via the link - and send it to: The Data Controller, Villiers Park Educational Trust, Royston Road, Foxton, Cambridge, CB22 6SE. Alternatively email us at dataprotection@villierspark.org.uk and we will make sure that this is handled in a swift and appropriate manner.If you do not want to receive information from us, please get in touch with us and we will change your preferences: 01223 872601 or dataprotection@villierspark.org.uk.How we protect your personal informationWe maintain the highest standards of data privacy and security to protect your personal details and other information about you because we want you to feel completely confident about the communications you receive from us. We regularly review our processes and procedures to protect your information from unauthorised access and use, accidental loss and/or destruction.How to Contact UsPlease contact our Data Controller, Christine Hall, on dataprotection@villierspark.org.uk or by calling us on 01223 872601.
